Good morning, James.
How are you feeling?
Wait. What?
It's perfectly normal to feel confused.
You just spent 120 years
in suspended animation.
What?
It's okay, James.
- It's Jim.
- Jim.
Just breathe. Everything is okay.
Where am I?
You're a passenger on the starship avalon,
the homestead company's
premier interstellar starliner.
We've nearly completed the voyage
from earth to your new home.
The colony world of homestead ii.
A new world. A fresh start.
Room to grow.
Yeah.
The avalon is on final approach.
For the next four months,
you'll enjoy space travel
at its most luxurious.
Food. Fun. Friends.
- My friends.
- That's right, Jim.
The ID band on your wrist is your key
to the wonders of the avalon.
You're in perfect health, Jim.
Let's get you to your cabin,
where you can get some rest.
You may be experiencing
post-hibernation sickness.
Your door will illuminate for you.
Welcome to your cabin,
your home until we make landfall.
Over the next four months,
you'll prepare for your new life
on homestead 1,
meet your fellow passengers,
take skill-building classes,
and learn about colonial living.
You've been assigned to learning group 38
for passengers with engineering
and technical trade skills.
Please scan your ID
to confirm luggage delivery.
Jim.
Please scan your ID
to confirm luggage delivery.
To help you recover from hibernation,
be sure to drink plenty of fluids.
Enjoy the rest of your voyage on the avalon,
a homestead company starship.
Good morning, one and all.
It's a beautiful morning
here on the starship avalon.
Whatever you do, don't get homesick,
get homestead.
Let's start things off
with one of my favorites back on earth.
No.
That's stupid.
Just own it. Own it, Jim.
You got a cool jacket.
Hello, passengers.
Will you all please take a seat.
Welcome, learning group 38.
Your introduction to colonial life.
Earth is a prosperous planet,
the cradle of civilization.
But for many, it's also overpopulated,
overpriced, overrated.
I'm sorry, I think I may be in the wrong...
Hold all questions till the end, please.
Sorry.
The colonies offer an alternative,
a better way of life.
Where are all the other...
And there's no colony
more beautiful than homestead ii,
the Jewel of the occupied world.
I'm sorry.
Where is everybody?
We are all on the starship avalon.
But I'm the only one here.
There are 5,000 passengers
and 258 crew members.
So why am I alone?
We're all in this together.
Hello?
Anybody here?
Please buckle up and secure any loose items.
This elevator will experience
a momentary lapse in gravity.
Grand concourse.
Hello.
Welcome to the grand concourse
aboard the avalon.
Can I help you?
I need to talk to a person.
A real live person, please?
What sort of person?
Personal trainer? Travel planner?
- Therapist?
- I don't know.
Somebody in charge.
The ship's steward
handles passenger affairs.
It's on level three of the grand concourse.
- Thank you.
- Happy to help.
Not good.
- Hello.
- Who's flying the ship?
The flight crew, the captain, the pilot,
the chief navigator...
Captain. I want to speak to the captain.
The captain rarely handles
passenger queries...
It's an emergency! Please.
The captain is usually found on the bridge,
in the command ring.
Bridge access requires special authorization.
You got to be kidding me.
Welcome to the observatory.
What can I show you?
We're supposed to land soon.
I'm the only one awake.
I don't understand. What can I show you?
Show me homestead ii.
Homestead ll is the fourth planet
in the bhakti system.
Right. And where are we?
We're in transit from earth to homestead ii.
We will arrive in approximately 90 years.
What?
We arrive at homestead ii
in 90 years, three weeks and one day.
No. Wait.
How long ago did we leave earth?
Approximately 30 years ago.
I woke up too soon.
Hello.
How do I send a message to earth?
Interstellar messages are sent by laser array.
This is an expensive service.
- Bite me.
- Happy to help.
Planet and connection?
Earth. The homestead company.
There are 30,826 contacts
listed under homestead company.
I'm emigrating to homestead ll
and I have an emergency.
I have a customer help line.
Sounds about right.
Begin message.
Hi. I'm Jim Preston.
I'm a passenger on the avalon.
I...
I think something went wrong
with my hibernation pod.
I woke up too soon.
And I mean, way too soon.
Nobody else is awake, and...
I don't know how to get back to sleep.
And the thing is, there's 90 years to go.
At this rate, I'm...
I'm sorry, I'm trying to fix this.
Maybe I missed something.
I could use a hand.
That's all.
Thank you.
Message sent.
Outstanding.
Message will arrive in 19 years.
Wait, what?
Earliest reply in 55 years.
Fifty-five years?
We apologize for the delay.
That will be $6,012.
- Afternoon.
- Man!
Is it good to see another face!
Thought I was the only one awake.
Who wants to sleep
on a beautiful day like this?
No, I mean we're in trouble.
We're not supposed to be here.
Well, I won't tell if you don't.
Our little secret.
What can I get for you?
What?
You look like a whiskey man.
Okay.
You're a robot.
Android. Technically.
Arthur's the name.
- Jim.
- Pleased to meet you, Jim.
How much do you know about this ship?
I don't know.
I know some things.
What do I do
if my hibernation pod malfunctions?
Hibernation pods are fail-safe.
They never malfunction.
Well, I woke up early.
Can't happen.
How long until we get to homestead ii?
About 90 years or so.
And when are all the passengers
supposed to wake up?
Not till the last four months.
How is it that I'm sitting here with you
with 90 years to go?
It's not possible for you to be here.
Well, I am.
Good morning.
It's a beautiful day here on the avalon.
So wake up, sunshine.
It's time to relax and enjoy your stay.
Please make a selection.
Sorry. The mocha cappuccino extreme
is reserved for gold-class passengers.
is reserved for...
I want the mocha cappuccino extreme.
Bill my room, please.
Food can be purchased in the ship's...
Sorry. The French roast...
Sorry. The pumpkin spice...
Sorry. Vanilla chai...
Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry.
Large coffee.
- Cream...
- Please enjoy your coffee.
Really?
Crew pod room access
requires special authorization.
Grand... Going...
Please make... level...
Grand concourse.
I'm screwed, Arthur.
Completely and ridiculously screwed.
Come on, now.
Every cloud has a silver lining.
Guess I am gonna die of old age on this ship.
We all die.
Even androids end up on the scrap heap.
I'm your only customer.
Why are you always polishing a glass?
Trick of the trade.
Makes people nervous
when a bartender just stands there.
So lay some bartender wisdom on me.
I'm lost in space here.
You're not where you want to be.
You feel like you're supposed
to be somewhere else.
You said it.
Well, say you could snap your fingers
and be wherever you wanted to be.
I bet you'd still feel this way.
Not in the right place.
Point is, you can't get so hung up
on where you'd rather be
that you forget how to make
the most of where you are.
What are you telling me?
Take a break from worrying
about what you can't control.
Live a little.
Welcome to the Vienna suite.
Yeah.
What?
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Yeah!
Make that a double jumbo shrimp.
Triple.
Dance-off.
All right.
I did exactly what you just did.
Large coffee.
You have had many, senor.
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Get out of here!
Come back. Hey.
Come here.
Welcome, Jim.
Please turn your attention
to the screens displaying safety tips.
These spacesuits are designed
to withstand the harsh environment of space.
The carbon fiber and polyamide construction
means your suit is both flexible and durable.
Remember, your spacesuit is your lifeline.
Slide the handle on the right
to release the air pressure.
Your magnetic boots are now engaged.
They can be deactivated
using the control panel on your arm.
Press the red button
to open the airlock door.
Have a wonderful time.
Tether attached.
Welcome back, Jim.
We hope you decide to join us again soon
for another thrilling experience.
Have a wonderful time.
Aurora.
Searching passenger profiles.
I'm Aurora Lane.
Passenger 1456. I'm a writer.
I think we tell each other stories
to know we're not alone, to make contact.
Your father was Oliver Lane,
a pulitzer prize-winning author.
No pressure, right?
My dad used to say,
"if you live an ordinary life,
“all you'll have are ordinary stories.
"You have to live a life of adventure."
So... Here I am.
Good morning.
We're starting over in every way.
I'll have to figure out
where to live, how to live,
who my friends will be.
It's like the first day of school.
If the school bus took 120 years to get there.
We're creating a culture...
You are funny.
Do you ever read something
and feel like it's written just for you?
I don't do a lot of reading.
She's good.
Who's that?
Aurora.
The sleeping girl.
You know, I'm not saying the universe is evil,
but it sure has a nasty sense of humor.
How is that?
You get to fly to another planet,
but you'll die along the way.
And you find the perfect woman
right in front of you...
Yet she's completely out of reach.
Yeah, I'll miss New York City.
Give me a cup of coffee
and a view of the Chrysler building,
and I can write all day.
They do have coffee on homestead ll, right?
They better have coffee.
If they don't, I have to turn around
and come back to earth.
Is there anything you regret leaving behind?
Yeah, I'll miss the trees in central park
turning in the fall.
I'll also miss crowds...
Say you were trapped on a desert island,
and you had the power
to wish somebody there with you.
You wouldn't be alone anymore.
But you'd be stranding the person
on the island.
Would you make that wish?
I don't know. I've never been on an island.
Okay, well, yeah.
Forget the island.
Let's say you figured out
how to do something
that would make your life
a million times better,
but you knew it was wrong
and there's no taking it back.
How do you do the math?
Jim, these are not robot questions.
I know how to wake Aurora up.
Well, that seems like a fine idea.
You could use some company.
I'd be stranding her on this ship
for the rest of her life.
Well, you can't do that.
What am I gonna do?
I'm here for you.
Arthur, you're a machine.
See? You can't feel that.
You don't have feelings.
See?
That doesn't hurt.
And you don't even mind.
'Cause you're not a person.
Don't even think about it.
No more Aurora talk.
I'm over it.
I'm moving on.
Don't even think about it!
What am I gonna do?
I'm just gonna sit and think about it?
I can't think about it, so I'm not going to.
That's the deal. I've made my decision.
I know what I'm doing.
I just cut it off.
I'm not... no more.
You won't hear me bring up her name again.
I'll never even mention her name again.
Done.
You can't do it.
Shaving off my beard.
Please don't do it.
Good morning, Aurora.
How are you feeling?
It's perfectly normal to feel confused.
You just spent 120 years
in suspended animation.
Grand concourse.
Hello?
Anybody?
Hello.
Hi.
Are you passenger or crew?
Passenger.
Jim Preston.
Aurora Lane.
Do you know what's going on?
Nobody else from my row woke up.
Same for me.
The crew's supposed to wake up
a month before we do,
but I haven't seen anybody.
The crew is still asleep.
Are you saying nobody's awake?
Just me.
Just you?
It's just us.
But somebody's got to land the ship
in a few weeks.
We will arrive in approximately 89 years.
Eighty-nine years?
The other passengers aren't late waking up.
We were early.
We need help.
Where's the crew?
The crew's in a secure hibernation room.
Everything important, the controls,
the reactors, the engines...
It's all behind firewalls.
There's no way through.
How long have you been awake?
A year and three weeks.
No. No, no, no.
No, this can't be happening.
We have to go back to sleep.
Aurora, we can't.
We just have to get back to our pods
and start them up again.
I can't find my pod. I can't find my pod.
I can't find my pod. I don't know which...
It doesn't matter.
- Aurora...
- I can't find it!
- Stop. Aurora...
- I can't find which one is mine!
- Stop.
- I don't know which one is mine!
- I'll help you.
- I can't...
Stop! It doesn't matter.
Putting somebody into hibernation
requires special equipment.
Remember the facility
where they put us under,
all the procedures we went through?
These pods are designed
to keep us in hibernation,
to wake us up at the right time,
but they can't put us back to sleep.
You don't think there's a way
back into hibernation?
No.
But there has to be.
There has to be.
9:00. Nighttime.
I know I should be
working the problem, but...
I can't even keep my eyes open.
You just came out of hibernation.
It's going to be a couple of days
before you're 100%.
You should get some rest.
Think I'm gonna have to.
I'll walk you to your cabin.
No, it's okay. I'll be all right.
Okay.
Good night, Aurora.
More than a year?
I can't imagine.
It must have been so hard for you.
It was.
Good night, Jim.
Please buckle up and secure any loose items.
- Whiskey, neat.
- Sure thing.
How's your day been?
Aurora's awake.
Congratulations.
You don't look happy.
Arthur, can you keep a secret?
Jim...
I'm not just a bartender, I'm a gentleman.
Don't tell Aurora that I woke her up.
She thinks it was an accident. Let me tell her.
Of course.
How can there be no way
to put someone back into hibernation?
What if a pod breaks down?
No hibernation pod has malfunctioned
in thousands of interstellar flights.
Well, I'm awake.
Hibernation pods are fail-safe.
Good morning.
- Have you eaten?
- No. I'm starving.
And this is the dumbest machine.
Happy to help.
Gold-class breakfast.
Well, you're a man of simple tastes.
I'm not a gold-class passenger.
French breakfast puff's above my pay grade.
What? This whole time?
- Yeah.
- What can I get you?
- No. No, I'm fine.
- Stop it.
Really. Okay.
Here you go.
Yeah.
So, I was thinking,
maybe there's another way to go to sleep.
What about the infirmary?
I checked it out.
It's just scanners and an autodoc.
There could be another hibernation machine
in the cargo hold.
I had that thought, too.
And then I read the manifest.
It's mostly farming stuff,
machines and trade goods.
Replacement parts
for computers and engineering.
We're not gonna find
a hibernation facility in a box.
- We could build our own.
- We can't.
Jim, you're not even trying.
I have tried everything.
For over a year, I...
I tried everything.
Well...
Well, I'm not ready to give up.
Infirmary.
What about research articles?
Any kind of technical documents.
Hibernation technology is proprietary.
The following articles deal with the subject
on a theoretical level.
New file. My voyage.
I boarded the avalon with an idea,
a destination.
Both now out of reach.
I've been awake for seven days.
Awake far too soon.
And I may well spend the rest of my life here,
in a steel world 1,000 meters long.
There's another passenger awake,
a mechanic named Jim Preston.
He seems to have accepted our fate.
But I'm scared.
I'm fighting to stay calm.
All the other passengers will sleep
for another 90 years
while I live out my life on this ship,
traveling forever...
Never arriving...
My only companion a total stranger.
Why did you do it?
Do what?
Emigrate. Leave earth.
I'm interviewing you.
You're what?
You were the first hibernation failure
in the history of space travel.
That makes you a story.
Who you gonna tell?
Posterity.
So, why did you give up your life on earth?
120-year space hibernation means
you'll never see your family or friends again.
You'll wake up in a new century
on a new planet.
It's the ultimate geographical suicide.
Well, I could ask you the same thing.
But it's my interview.
Were you running away from something?
No.
- Everything was okay.
- So?
Well, I guess I just wanted a new world,
I don't know, a fresh start.
That's homestead company advertising.
- Is it?
- Jim.
I know. I guess. You're right.
Back on earth, when something breaks,
you don't fix it, you replace it.
The colonies, they have problems to solve.
They're my kind of problems.
And a mechanic is somebody.
This is a new world still being built.
I could build a house and live in it.
Open country. Room to grow.
Now you're back to slogans.
Can't slogans be true?
Do you know how much
homestead company
made off its first planet?
Eight quadrillion dollars.
That's eight million billions.
Colony planets
are the biggest business going.
Did you pay full price for your ticket?
No. I'm in a desirable trade.
So they fill your head with dreams,
discount your ticket,
and you fly off to populate their planet
and give homestead
20% of everything that you make
for the rest of your life.
Not to mention the debt you run up
on this fancy starship.
So all you see here is 5,000 suckers?
I see zeros
on the homestead company's bottom line.
I see 5,000 men and women
changing their lives.
For 5,000 different reasons.
You don't know these people.
I'm a journalist. I know people.
Really?
This one.
Is he a banker, a teacher or a gardener?
- Banker.
- He's a gardener.
And her. Is she a...
Madison, Donna or a Lola?
Donna's too serious for that hair.
Lola.
- Madison.
- Shit!
All right, chef, accountant or midwife?
She has to be a midwife.
There's no way you just made that one up.
Yeah. She's a midwife.
I didn't know they still had midwives.
I like her. We'd be friends.
You think you can see that?
Don't you?
I do.
- A round-trip ticket?
- That's right.
I was gonna fly to homestead ii,
live for a year,
and then right back to earth.
I don't get it. I left earth for a new life,
but you end up back where you started?
I end up in the future.
Two hundred and fifty years in the future,
on earth, which is still
the center of civilization,
like it or not.
And I'll be the only writer to ever travel
to a colony world and come back.
I'll have a story no one else can tell.
What story?
Humanity's flight to the stars.
The greatest migration in human history.
It's the biggest story there is.
But you won't know
any of the people who are reading it.
But they'd be reading it.
Or they would have been.
I'll never write it now.
I don't know if I'll ever write again.
Jim, I can't think of anything else to try
to save us.
And I don't even want to
think about it anymore.
What is there to do around here?
- Are you serious?
- Dead serious.
- Partner mode.
- Let's get it on!
Come on, get in power mode.
You just stand here.
And then we repeat what they do.
Is there anything else we can do?
- Just do the...
- Okay.
- You don't have to.
- Okay. I can...
- Beat down!
- Hey!
Here we go. Let's see it.
- Why you smiling?
- Auroral Aurora!
'Cause I'm up two points.
Who's the lovely lady?
This is Aurora.
Aurora. A pleasure.
- I can't!
- You did great!
Okay, one more time.
One more time, let's see it.
Yes!
I swear, I didn't wear pants for a month.
Seven weeks and two days, to be exact.
The man has no shame.
Well, you're a little lacking
in that area yourself, Arthur.
I laughed at the man with no pants
until I realized I have no legs.
For a minute,
I almost forgot my life is in ruins.
I'm sorry.
What for?
I'm gonna go to bed.
Good night.
- All right.
- Good night, Aurora.
She is wonderful.
Excellent choice.
Hello.
Hi.
Here you go.
Is he asking me on a date?
Do you need a pen?
She didn't seem that impressed.
"Love to." She wrote, "love to."
You have a visitor.
You clean up pretty good yourself.
You went shopping.
I went shoplifting.
Evening.
What can I get for you?
I'll have a Manhattan, please.
- Whiskey, rocks.
- Coming up.
You two look fine this evening.
Thank you, Arthur. We're on a date.
Very nice.
Took you long enough to ask.
I was giving you space.
Space.
The one thing I do not need more of.
That was so good.
It wasn't easy getting a reservation.
They're probably gonna want us
to give up our table.
I'm getting a lot of dirty looks.
Very popular tonight.
So how's your book coming?
I don't really know what it is yet.
My dad, he used to always
write about his life,
but he had stories.
He'd sailed around Antarctica.
He was a war reporter.
He had lovers.
He wrote about his daughter.
He wrote about you?
Yeah. I grew up reading
about myself in his books.
How was that?
Not always easy.
A little more than you wanted
to know about yourself.
And then, when I was 17,
he had a heart attack.
Right at his keypad.
End of story.
That was so serious. I'm sorry.
We need more wine.
I like hearing about your life.
Thanks.
Why are we here?
You'll see.
Best show in town.
So you've done this before?
Yeah.
And it's safe?
No.
Reasonably safe.
Hop in. You're next.
What about my dress?
Right.
Turn around.
Tether attached.
What are you doing?
Do you trust me?
Thank you.
You're the most beautiful woman
I've ever seen.
You kill me.
You okay?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
It's just...
Yeah, I know.
So, I'm seeing someone.
You'll never guess who.
We're the last two people in the world
who would ever get together.
But here we are.
The last two people in the world.
What's that?
I'm writing, Arthur. Hush.
Jim and I live in accidental happiness.
Like castaways,
making their home on strange shores.
"Strange shores." I love it.
You do? You don't have to say that.
- I know.
- You're not gonna eat this.
Does that seem fishy to you?
Keep reading.
It's funny.
We all have dreams.
We plan our futures
like we're the captains of our fates.
But we're passengers.
We go where fate takes us.
I can't help Arthur!
This isn't the life we planned.
But it's ours.
And for the first time in my life,
I don't feel alone.
We weren't supposed to find each other.
But we did.
He makes me feel like my life isn't over.
Like it's just beginning.
How was your day?
Good. I wrote a few pages.
Did you find anything that can help us?
- I did.
- Are they real?
I cut them myself.
You know, for two unlucky people,
we sure got pretty lucky.
Attention.
You may wish to proceed to a viewing area.
The avalon will slingshot
around the star arcturus.
Look!
Oh, my god!
That was amazing.
A red giant.
The universe's present to you.
What?
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday to you
happy birthday, dear Aurora
happy birthday to you
a birthday drink for the birthday girl.
Aren't you going to ask for my ID?
I might not be old enough to drink.
I would never ask your age
in front of a gentleman.
Jim's no gentleman.
Anyway, there's no secrets
between me and Jim.
- Is that so?
- You heard the lady.
I will be right back.
This is a perfect birthday drink. Thank you.
I remember this day a year ago.
Jim was so looking forward to meeting you.
What?
How could he be looking forward to it?
He spent months deciding
whether to wake you up.
He couldn't stop talking about you.
Jim woke me up?
Yes.
He said it was the hardest decision of his life.
But I see it worked out just fine.
What?
Did you wake me up?
Yes, I woke you up.
How...
How could you do it?
I tried not to.
I'm gonna be sick.
I can't see.
Aurora, please...
Stay away from me!
I can't get off this ship. I can't get off.
No!
Oh, god.
Can I talk to you?
Aurora,
I know nothing I can say will make this okay.
But please listen.
I was so alone for so long.
It felt like I was disappearing.
The night I first saw you, I was ready to...
You saved my life.
And I know that's no excuse for what I did.
I read everything you wrote,
and I fell in love with your voice
and with the way your mind works.
I fell in love with you.
And all of a sudden,
it was like I wasn't trapped anymore.
My pointless life suddenly had meaning.
And I wish I could take it back.
But I can't.
Aurora, I don't want to lose you.
I don't care!
I don't care what you want!
I don't care why you woke me up!
You took my life!
Please stand by.
Your suite's control center is rebooting.
I envy you, Arthur.
How so?
You have a purpose.
You're always happy.
How's your book coming along?
I've never written about myself before.
I think it's some of the best work
I've ever done,
and I don't even know why I'm doing it.
There's only one person who could read it,
and I can't stand him.
They say time heals all wounds.
Broken hearts aren't that simple, Arthur.
You wouldn't understand.
Arthur!
Tuesday's my day with Arthur.
It's Wednesday.
The bar's all yours.
What'll you have? Whiskey?
Coffee.
Aurora! We love you!
What are we gonna do without you?
We'll miss you so...
You're the bravest woman I know.
Bye, Aurora!
I promise that I will think of you every day.
When you wake up, I'll be gone,
but just know that I will never forget you.
You're my best friend.
You were never happy here. I know.
Nothing was ever enough for you.
You know, you don't have to go.
You could do
whatever it is you have to do right here.
But...
Since you're going, here's my wish.
I hope you finally find someone
who fills your heart, and
I hope you let him in.
I hope you realize you don't have to do
something amazing to be happy.
You know, have fun,
take chances.
Okay.
I love you, Aurora.
Bye.
Morning, Arthur!
- Coffee, please.
- Coming up.
Are you soiling my barstool?
You want to make things,
you got to get your hands dirty.
And what have you been making?
Improvements.
Grand concourse.
First floor.
Gold-class breakfast.
This is deck chief Gus mancuso.
Who the hell planted a tree on my ship?
- Who did that?
- I did.
Who are you?
Jim Preston.
Aurora Lane.
Anybody else awake?
Just me and him.
How far along are we?
Eighty-eight years to go.
Hibernation failure.
They said that couldn't happen.
Three people, three pod failures.
You have no idea
how long I've been trying to get in there.
Now that you're in, don't touch anything.
This is where you work?
No, this is flight crew. I'm a deck chief.
Ops, navigation, comm.
Unauthorized personnel.
Sorry.
If I'm reading this right, we're still on course.
So whatever's wrong with the ship,
navcom is still on the job.
There's something wrong with the ship?
Three pod failures?
Yeah, there's something wrong.
Question is what.
That's strange.
We should be getting diagnostics
from all over the ship right here,
but there's no data.
Got to check all the systems manually.
Can't we turn the ship around,
go back to earth?
No, we're doing 50% of light speed.
Turning back would
take just as much time as going on.
Well, there's got to be something we can do.
Sorry. We're going where we're going.
You okay?
Hibernation hangover.
Get it all the time.
Grand concourse.
Two years?
Any more trees I need to know about?
Look out!
Never seen that before.
These robots have been breaking down.
This guy makes fifteen?
Fifteen.
The breakfast bar went crazy today.
- Yeah, and an elevator.
- Last week, my door broke.
- I was trapped in my cabin for two days.
- You were?
Things like that don't happen.
Not on this ship.
There are 16 of these tech stations
on every deck.
Dock your slate.
Data syncs automatically. Got it?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
You take decks one and two.
You take decks three and four.
I'm going down to the hibernation bay,
check our pods.
Well, that should be interesting.
Ain't you supposed to be
making your rounds?
I'm finished.
I checked your pod.
Problem's very simple.
The clock chip's burnt out.
It ain't supposed to happen,
but pretty simple.
My pod's more complicated.
Bunch of system failures that
all happened at the same time.
Whole damn thing went haywire.
Explains why I'm feeling so bad.
But Aurora's pod...
You did this.
Yeah.
All this time, I'm thinking
you're one lucky son of a bitch
to get stuck with Aurora.
It wasn't luck, was it?
No.
She knows?
She knows.
How long were you alone?
A year.
Still...
Damn.
Data received.
- Data received.
- Same as Jim's.
Interpolating data.
System shutdowns...
Everywhere, but no apparent connection.
You saw the hibernation pods?
I saw them.
Data received.
So you know
what Jim did.
Yeah.
And?
- It's not my...
- He woke me up.
He took away my life.
I know, and I'm sorry, but there's work I'd...
It's murder.
You're right, Aurora.
But the drowning man will always try
and drag somebody down with him.
It ain't right, but the man's drowning.
This one makes 16.
Hey. You okay?
- You should go rest.
- Yeah.
But just a couple hours,
and then back at it first thing in the morning.
I was in the pool when the gravity gave out.
Are you okay?
We need to find Gus.
Gus! Gus!
Gravity loss means that whatever's wrong
is starting to hit the big-ticket items.
Not good.
Every failure's a burnt out processor.
Everything on board's thinking too hard.
Why?
Computer, display these failures over time.
Processing timeline.
Cascade failure.
It started two years ago. Power surge.
Seventeen failures in one day.
Including hibernation pod 1498.
That's me.
Woke me up.
- What happened that day?
- Something big.
A major system went down somewhere.
Everything else on board
is trying to pick up the load,
but the load's too heavy.
Whatever started this, we got to find it.
And fix it.
How bad can this get?
Give me risk analysis based on this data.
Extrapolating.
A mission-critical failure is imminent.
Failing systems.
Life support, fusion reactor...
So we're stranded.
Hibernation bay, ion drive...
On a sinking ship.
Main engineering.
Not a lot of things big enough
to hit this ship that hard.
With diagnostics out,
we'll have to find it ourselves.
Where do we start?
Gus!
Scan complete. Analyzing data.
What's it say is wrong with me?
It's a few things.
612 disorders found.
Get me out of here.
What's the prognosis?
Critical diagnoses cannot be discussed
without a doctor in attendance.
Override on my authority. ID 2317.
Lay it on me, doc.
Pansystemic necrosis.
Progressive organ failure. Cause, unknown.
My goofy hibernation pod. That's the cause.
- What's the treatment?
- Various treatments are possible.
None will meaningfully extend
the patient's life.
How long have I got?
Your end-of-life transition
is already underway.
These sedatives will alleviate your suffering
during these final hours.
Gus.
I need a minute.
We are experiencing difficulties in flight.
- Gus!
Where could he be?
For your own safety,
please return to your cabins.
We are experiencing difficulties in flight.
For your own safety,
please return to your cabins.
Should've took the damn pills.
- I'll go get them.
- No. Stay here with me.
Sit down.
You two take care of each other.
My ID.
Get you where you need to go.
Fix the ship.
Find out what's wrong with her.
How do I look?
You look magnificent.
Ladies love the dress blues.
What do we do now?
This can't be good.
I'm going back to engineering.
Can you fix this?
I need your help.
Let's go.
Arthur!
Main engineering.
Can't we wake up some of the crew?
It'll take them too long to recover.
We don't have that kind of time.
What are we even looking for?
Something broken. Something big.
Come on.
Is it broken?
It seems okay. What's next?
Power plant. This way.
Come on.
The whole section's closed off.
Something's wrong.
We're looking for wrong.
Try to open it.
Warning. Pressure fault.
Lockdown initiated.
- Please secure all doors.
- Hold on!
Warning. Dangerous oxygen level.
Please secure all doors.
Dangerous oxygen level.
Grab it!
Pressurizing cabin unsuccessful.
Pressure normalized.
Oxygen level restored.
- There's a...
- End lockdown.
A hole in the ship.
More than one.
How did that even happen?
The ship's supposed to be meteor-proof.
I guess one got through.
It's hot.
I think we found it.
It's the reactor-control computer.
This is what hit us two years ago.
Jim...
How can we fix this?
We're gonna die.
There's replacement parts for everything.
- Light.
- Sorry.
Soon as I pull this module,
the entire computer's gonna shut down.
Well, what happens then?
I'll get it back up as quickly as I can.
Hurry!
- Jim!
- Okay.
Control computer restored.
Venting reactor.
- But we fixed it!
- Reactor vent failed.
Manual override required.
Vent failure.
- Come on!
- Jim.
Outer door nonresponsive.
What does that mean?
The outer door is jammed.
We've got to open that door
and cool the reactor down,
or the whole ship is gonna blow.
- How?
- I got to go out there.
Open it from the outside.
I open the door, I get clear.
- You blow that fire into space.
- You get clear?
You can talk to me through this.
What happens to you when that door opens?
Heat shield. It might help.
You might need this.
It's gonna be okay.
I better go.
Jim. Jim.
Come back to me.
I can't live on the ship without you.
Warning.
Temperature critical.
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
- Are you okay?
- Nothing.
- Go.
- You sure?
Go.
I'm at the vent tube.
New anchor point. Reset tether.
I see the door.
Temperature level rising.
Warning. Temperature critical.
Containment unstable.
- Where are you?
- I'm at the door.
I'm ready. Just say when.
Here goes.
The door won't open.
I'll have to bypass it.
Temperature level rising.
Jim, come on!
Please hurry!
- Okay, I'm trying it again.
- Tell me when you're clear.
- No!
- What?
What's going on?
Jim?
Jim!
The door won't stay open.
I think I have to stay here.
Hold the door open.
What?
No!
No way! Get out of there!
I can't.
Jim.
We're out of time.
- Containment unstable.
- Jim?
Vent the reactor.
No! You don't understand!
If I open the door right now, it'll kill you!
I'm hoping not.
Come back in. We'll think of something else.
There is nothing else.
Jim!
- It's okay.
- No!
- It's not okay!
- Aurora...
Warning. Temperature level exceeded.
This isn't what you said was gonna happen!
Aurora, this ship is gonna go.
I don't care! You die, I die.
There are 5,000 other people
on this ship, Aurora.
We have to do this.
Maximum pressure reached.
Do it. Now.
Maximum cabin pressure reached.
Temperature dropping.
Jim.
- Jim?
- Vent successful.
Rebooting process initiated.
Jim, please say something.
Suit pressure dropping.
Return to ship immediately.
Aurora?
It worked!
You did it! You can come in!
Yeah, about that.
What's the matter? Are you hurt?
I got blown out of the tube.
- What?
- My tether broke.
I can't get back to the ship.
I'll come out. I'll come out. I'll pull you in.
Warning. Oxygen level critical.
Return to ship immediately.
Aurora, I'm sorry.
For everything.
Shut up. I'm coming.
I wish we'd have met in 90 years.
I'd have built you a house.
I'd have read your book.
It's gonna be great.
Tether attached.
Locate Jim Preston.
Jim Preston located.
I'm coming to get you.
Jim!
I'm sorry. The patient is dead.
Well, resuscitate him!
Postmortem operations require
authorized medical supervision.
No.
Jim.
Override!
Override on my authority!
ID 1-7...
Two... Two. Two.
2-3-1-7.
2-3-1-7! ID 2-3-1-7!
Resuscitation.
Multiple procedures are not recommended.
Override! Do it now!
Executing.
Hi!
Jim!
Hey, Jim.
You brought me back.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Be still.
Of course.
There's something I have to show you.
In command mode, it turns out
the autodoc has an option
called stabilize and suspend.
It stops all metabolic activity.
What are you saying?
With Gus's ID, it can be like hibernation
inside the autodoc.
You can go back to sleep.
But there's only one autodoc.
Yeah.
And you're gonna lay down in it
and fall asleep.
And you'll wake up on homestead ii.
And you'll write your book.
You'd finish your journey.
You'd do what you set out to do.
You'd be alone.
I've been alone before.
And I'll be fine.
But I would never see you again.
I'll come and visit you.
Tuesday is my day with Arthur.
Lovely as ever.
Thank you, Arthur.
You're looking very well yourself.
Thanks to you.
What's that?
Something I've wanted to give you
for a long time.
It's beautiful.
Took you long enough to ask.
Champagne.
I'll wait.
Hell of a life.
Crew wake-up process initiated.
My fellow passengers,
if you're reading this,
then the starship avalon
has reached its destination.
Grand concourse.
A lot happened while you slept.
A friend once said,
"you can't get so hung up
on where you'd rather be
that you forget to make
the most of where you are.”
We got lost along the way.
But we found each other.
And we made a life.
A beautiful life.
Together.